# **DU NGUYEN**

#### **PROFILE**

Software engineer with experience in developing fullstack web applications and backend services. Masters in Software Engineering from the Technical University of Denmark with a focus on Data Science, User Experience and Cognition.

Startup experience having worked with two startups in the incubation phase and V1 phase with both B2C and B2B focus.

Currently working at Microsoft on Microsoft Dynamics Marketing with designing, coding and maintaining the SDK and the data sync feature between Dynamics Marketing and Dynamics 365, and on developing new frontend features for upcoming versions of Dynamics Marketing.

Experience in Microsoft: Running and supporting a 24/7 online service, shipping multiples releases, designing and coding features, debugging and problem solving issues from live site incidents, strong cross team collaboration with Dynamics 365 teams, Azure teams and SRE and support teams. Customer obsession in live site incidents.

Proficient in C#, .NET, Python, Java, Javascript, HTML, CSS, Typescript with experience in cloud computing and Azure.

# PROFESSIONAL ACHIEVEMENTS

### **MICROSOFT**

Designing and coding features on data sync, APIs and SDK on Dynamics Marketing.

Shipping a major release and multiple minor releases on Dynamics Marketing.

Improving reliability and decreasing number of live site incidents of SDK and data synchronization by >80% in a 6-month period

Managing and leading teams of vendors

Strong debugging and problem solving skills in finding and fixing hidden bugs.

Close cross-team collaboration with SRE, Support, Azure Dev and Dynamics 365 teams.

Developing a graphical workflow designer on the Dynamics 365 platform

#### **EASYSIZE**

Design and implementation of data infrastructure

Implementation of automated data munging scripts

Implementation of analytics service

Machine learning experiments for core business needs

#### **COPY ME THAT**

Design and implementation of API

**Building Android app** 

SKILLS C# and .NET

SQL, SQL Server

Python

Javascript, Typescript, HTML, CSS

Azure

#### **WORK HISTORY**

#### SOFTWARE ENGINEER, MICROSOFT

July 2015 - current

#### **BACKEND DEVELOPER, EASYSIZE**

January 2015 – February 2015, May 2015 – June 2015

#### FULL STACK WEB DEVELOPER, COPY ME THAT

September 2014 – December 2014

#### **EDUCATION**

### M.SC IN DIGITAL MEDIA ENGINEERING, TECHNICAL UNIVERSITY OF DENMARK, 2014

Thesis: Improving game experience using dynamic difficulty adjustment based on physiological

signals.

Focus areas: Data science, user experience, cognition

#### **B.SC IN SOFTWARE ENGINEERING, TECHNICAL UNIVERSITY OF DENMARK, 2011**

Thesis: Implementing a search engine

Focus areas: Algorithms, software engineering, computer science

# SELECTED PUBLICATIONS

## DO'S AND DON'TS OF CODE REVIEWS

# BLICATIONS <a href="https://medium.com/@dunguyen/the-dos-and-don-ts-of-code-reviews-dff2be5aa89a">https://medium.com/@dunguyen/the-dos-and-don-ts-of-code-reviews-dff2be5aa89a</a>

#### A PERSONAL PRODUCTIVITY SYSTEM

https://medium.com/@dunguyen/a-personal-productivity-system-964e32e49d40

#### WHY WORK AT STARTUPS

https://medium.com/easysize-guests-wall/why-work-at-startups-305425d14b39

#### **MORNING ROUTINES**

https://medium.com/@dunguyen/morning-routines-4966d72c77d4